之前在那些即将死去的人身上......
Previously on
Those About To Die...
地球上最伟大的城市的人们，让游戏开始吧！
People of the greatest city
on Earth, let the games begin!
你丈夫打得好，他会赢木剑。
Your husband fights well,
he will win the wooden sword.
这是关于什么的？
What's this about?
- 她现在是罗马的财产。-不！请！
- She is now the property of Rome.
- No! Please!
这是怎麽？
What is this?
我已经注册了 Ludus。
I've enrolled myself
in the the Ludus.
领航员今天下午抵达奥斯蒂亚。
The navigator arrives
in Ostia this afternoon.
杀了他，此时此地。
Kill him, here and now.
我有一件最重要的事情要送给提图斯皇帝。
I have something of the utmost
importance to give to the Emperor Titus.
今天，我们似乎孤军奋战。
It seems, today, we fight alone.
没有人知道他们会让我们面对什么。一支军队。动物。
There's no telling what they'll
pit us against. An army. Animals.
我们将背靠背。
We'll go back to back.
让我们看看我们可以带走多少。
Let's see how many
we can take with us.
谢谢。
Thank you.
因为你教给我的东西，诺斯曼。
For what you have
taught me, Northman.
不。
No.
谢谢你，我的努米底亚兄弟。
Thank you, my Numidian brother.
今天，我们一起生活，或者一起死去。
Today, we live together,
or we die together.
火与冰。
Fire and ice.
兄弟，你似乎很激动。
Brother, you seem agitated.
我唯一担心的是首届奥运会是否完美。
My only concern is that the
Inaugural Games are perfect.
好吧，也许奥斯蒂亚凉爽的空气会让你平静下来。
Well, perhaps the cool
air of Ostia will calm you.
- 奥斯蒂亚？-是的。
- Ostia?
- Yes.
在我们完成这一天的游戏后，导航员在那里等着我们。
A navigator waits for us there
after we finish this day of games.
士兵！去找禁卫军。移动。
Soldier! Go get the
Praetorians. Move.
士兵，让大家退后！回来！
Soldier, keep everybody
back! Get back!
我说回去！
I said get back!
士兵，让他们远离。我不想让任何人靠近这里，明白吗？
Soldier, keep them away. I don't
want anybody near here, understand?
禁卫军除外。快点！
Except for Praetorians. Move it!
跟我来。
Come with me.
拜托，拜托，告诉我你为什么要带她去。
Please, please, just tell
me why you are taking her.
这个门口没有女人。
No women at this gate.
不，不，拜托。我是她的母亲。
No, no, please. I'm her mother.
我需要知道这是关于什么的。
I need to know
what this is about.
滚开！
Fuck off!
你怎么敢这样跟我说话？
How dare you
talk to me like this?
走开！
Go away!
- 我是我妈妈，没有她我不会离开。-离开！
- I'm her mother, I won't leave without her.
- Leave!
你不能那样逮捕人！
You can't arrest
people like that!
你们这些混蛋！
You bastards!
罗马市民！我们向您介绍...
Citizens of Rome!
We present you...
一对战士。
a warrior pair.
-加油！-夸！夸！
- Come on!
- Kwame! Kwame!
我们不是角斗士，而是死在罗马军团士兵的手中。
Instead of gladiators, we are to die
at the hands of Roman legionnaires.
我父亲也是。
As did my father.
好。一个战士的死亡。
Good. A warrior's death.
两个角斗士背靠背战斗，
Two gladiators having
fought back to back,
作为野蛮的阿喀琉斯和感性的帕特洛克罗斯，
as savage Achilles,
and sensuous Patroclus,
快朋友在生死中联系在一起。
fast friends bonded
in life and death.
维果，北方人！
Viggo, the Northman!
还有狮子杀手夸梅！
And Kwame, the Lion Killer!
- 加油夸梅！- 加油夸梅！
- Come on Kwame!
在11场胜利之后，今天，
After 11 victories, today,
维果战斗
Viggo fights
伟大的...
the Great...
夸！
Kwame!
无敌弗拉玛的杀手！
Killer of the invincible Flamma!
这两个，最伟大的角斗士，
These two, the
greatest of all gladiators,
将，为了你的快乐，
will, for your pleasure,
现在互相争斗，
fight each other now,
至死不渝！
to the death!
角斗士。
Gladiators.
聘！
Engage!
夸。要坚强，兄弟，要坚强。
Kwame. Be strong,
brother, be strong.
我支持你。
I have your back.
来！
Come!
战斗！战斗！
Fight! Fight!
你是个怪物。他们带走了我的女儿！
You're a monster.
They've taken my daughter!
他们把她带到哪里去了？
Where have they taken her?
哪里？
Where?
我已经付了票！
I've paid my ticket!
来吧，战斗！
Come on, fight!
- 战斗，战斗，战斗！- 战斗，战斗，战斗！
- Fight, fight, fight!
这是娱乐的一部分吗？
This is part of
the entertainment?
我预料到了这一点。
I expected this.
罗马市民们，我向你们介绍......
Citizens of Rome,
I present to you...
朱拉！
Jula!
狮子杀手的小妹妹，夸梅！
Little sister of the
Lion Killer, Kwame!
朱拉！
Jula!
一个奴隶。罗马的财产。
A slave. The property of Rome.
还有北方人的儿子维果。
And the son of the
Northman, Viggo.
七岁，父亲眼中的光芒。
Seven years old, and
the light of his father's eye.
不。不。
No. No.
勇敢的角斗士们，还有什么比这更能鼓励战斗的呢，
What better encouragement
to fight, brave gladiators,
但是为了挽救家人的生命？
but to save the
lives of your family?
谁会死？
Who will die?
谁会活下来？
And who will live?
不。
No.
你设计了这种娱乐活动吗？
Did you devise
this entertainment?
哥哥。
Brother.
这是你的主意吗？
Was this your idea?
-是的。- 哦，好吧，
- Yes.
- Oh, well,
然后女神 Discordia 就住在你里面。
then the goddess
Discordia lives within you.
只有狡猾的头脑才能召唤出这样的事情。
Only a devious mind
could conjure such a thing.
我的朋友，我别无选择，只能杀了你。
My friend, I have no
choice but to kill you.
请原谅我。
Please forgive me.
如果你成功了，就不需要宽恕了。
If you succeed, no
forgiveness is needed.
罪魁祸首将归咎于这些贪婪的狼......
The blame will lie with
these ravening wolves...
罗穆卢斯的私生子。
Bastard children of Romulus.
夸！
Kwame!
嘿，姑娘！那个女人在哪里？
Hey, girl! Where's that woman?
特纳克斯。
Tenax.
他与 Aedile Ludi 合作。我在哪里可以找到他？
He works with the Aedile
Ludi. Where do I find him?
特纳克斯，他在里面的某个地方。
Tenax, he's somewhere inside.
分头行动，找到他，杀了他。
Split up, find him, kill him.
是时候收拾残局了。
It's time to tie up loose ends.
所以我无话可说。
So there is nothing I can say.
你确定要离开吗？
You're certain about leaving?
我很想带你一起去。
I would so love to
take you with me.
但你知道他们对偷马贼做了什么。
But you know what
they do to horse thieves.
艾莉亚，是朱拉！
Elia, it's Jula!
- 他们把她带到了圆形剧场！-什么？
- They've taken her to the amphitheatre!
- What?
他们利用她来强迫她的兄弟与他最好的朋友战斗。
They're using her to force her
brother to fight his best friend.
不！
No!
奇怪的是，看着两个所谓的忠诚朋友......
Strangely compelling to watch
two supposedly loyal friends...
可以称他们为家人，
could call them family,
战斗至死。
fighting to the death.
你不觉得吗，兄弟？
Don't you think, brother?
不要！
Don't!
这里。
Here.
嘿，你不能把你他妈的马留在这里。
Hey, you can't leave
your fucking horse here.
哦！
Oh!
夸！夸！夸！
Kwame! Kwame! Kwame!
停！停！
Stop! Stop!
那是你的儿子吗？
Is that your son?
那里。
There.
-起床！起床！-起床！
- Get up! Get up!
- Get up!
大！
Da!
维果
Viggo
英勇奋战。
has fought bravely.
让他活下去。
Let him live.
住！
Live!
住！住！住！
Live! Live! Live!
让他活下去
Let him live
再次为你而战！
to fight for you again!
住！住！住！
Live! Live! Live!
给他四分之一！
Give him quarter!
住！住！住！住！
Live! Live! Live! Live!
我有一个决定要做，兄弟。
I have a decision
to make, brother.
怜悯还是死亡？这是什么？
Mercy or death? What's it to be?
怜悯。
Mercy.
也许不是今天。
Perhaps not today.
-不！-不！
- No!
-不 不！什么？-什么？
- No, no! What?
- What?
不！
No!
没关系，儿子。
It's all right, son.
没关系。
It's all right.
你将与众神同在，
You will rest with the Gods,
并在我的梦中拜访我。
and visit me in my dreams.
请。请尽你所能
Please. Please do what you can
为了让我的儿子活着。
to keep my son alive.
我会的。我会的。
I will. I will.
死亡之屋。
The house of death.
我不会再有这个了。
I will have no more of this.
木剑！木剑！
Wooden sword! Wooden sword!
哥哥。
Brother.
木剑！木剑！
Wooden sword! Wooden sword!
这些游戏，
These games,
我们的城市，
our city,
我们的帝国，
our empire,
颂扬其最重要的美德。
celebrates its most
important virtue.
武士气概，
Martial valor,
和对罗马的责任。
and duty to Rome.
随着他今天的胜利，
With his victory today,
让这个角斗士
let this gladiator
庆祝自由！
celebrate freedom!
-夸！夸！夸！-夸！夸！夸！
- Kwame! Kwame! Kwame!
夸！夸！夸！
Kwame! Kwame! Kwame!
释放她。
Free her.
这个角斗士
This gladiator
已经赢得了权利
has earned the right
活在他的自由中
to live in his freedom
然而，他认为合适！
however he sees fit!
让他的姿态
Let his gesture
留！
stay!
拿去吧。
Take it.
你现在是自由的。
You are free now.
你是自由的。
You are free.
朱拉。
Jula.
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
谢谢。
Thank you.
去。
Go.
来。
Come.
谢谢。
Thank you.
夸！夸！夸！
Kwame! Kwame! Kwame!
带她去特纳克斯的公寓，在那里等我。
Take her to Tenax's
apartment and wait for me there.
我们得谈谈。
We need to talk.
去。去。
Go. Go.
夸！夸！夸！
Kwame! Kwame! Kwame!
怎么了？
What's wrong?
我生了你的孩子。
I bear your child.
你为什么不告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me?
因为我害怕它会让你离开。
Because I was afraid it
would make you leave.
朱拉。
Jula.
我哪儿也不去。
I'm not going anywhere.
主啊，我们护送奥斯蒂亚的队伍已经上马了。
Our escort to Ostia has
mounted already, Lord.
很好。哥哥
Very well. Brother,
我们在奥斯蒂亚有业务要处理。
we have business
in Ostia to attend to.
我想如果我留下来是最好的。
I think it would
be best if I stayed.
你的皇帝
Your Emperor
命令它。
commands it.
诺斯曼的儿子，杀了他。
The Northman's son, kill him.
你听到了。杀了他。
You heard me. Kill him.
杀了那个男孩！
Kill the boy!
阿伦！不！不！
Ahren! No! No!
不！
No!
不！不！不！
No! No! No!
哥哥！
Brother!
有了这个，
And with this,
首届运动会的第一天闭幕。
the first day of the
Inaugural Games closes.
这是谁干的？
Who did this?
我们不知道，凯撒。
We don't know, Caesar.
没有人看到发生了什么。
Nobody saw what happened.
这是你的杰作。
This is your handiwork.
不。
No.
带她去皇宫。
Take her to the palace.
是的，我的主人。你听到了。
Yes, my lord. You heard him.
到奥斯蒂亚。
To Ostia.
你这个肮脏的，背叛的狗屎。
You filthy, betraying shit.
没有背叛。
There is no betrayal.
只有生存。
Only survival.
你是个赌徒。你只是输了。
You're a gambler.
You simply lost.
图密善将死在他哥哥的手里，
Domitian will die by
his brother's hand,
你会死在我的剑下。
you will die by my sword here.
我们的小安排将和你一起死去。
And our little arrangement
will die along with you.
生存。
Survival.
还有 1000 万塞斯特斯。
And the 10 million sesterces.
我们都有开支。
We all have expenses.
特纳克斯！
Tenax!
永远不要让士兵与街头霸王对抗。
Never pit a soldier
against a street fighter.
你背叛了我。
You betrayed me.
你撒谎了。
You lied.
也许被背叛了，但我从未对你撒谎。
Betrayed, perhaps,
but I never lied to you.
我杀了一个人，付出的代价要少得多。
I've killed a man for far less.
我相信你有。
I'm sure you have.
拥抱墙壁。
Hug the wall.
我稍后会和你打交道。
I'll deal with you later.
大家，快回来！
Everyone, get back!
不 不！不，不，不，不，不！
No, no! No, no, no, no, no!
你做了什么？
What have you done?
我不得不这样做。
I had to.
我不明白你。
I don't understand you.
你从来没有这样做过。
You never did.
马尼利乌斯说他要付多少钱？
How much did Manilius
say he was going to pay?
我们有命令要杀了你。
We have orders to kill you.
多少？
How much?
十万，每个。
A hundred thousand, each.
我付给他1000万。
I paid him 10 million.
跟我来，你可以分享所有这些。
Come with me, and
you can share all of that.
木已成舟。
The die is cast.
嘿！
Hey!
我会把它引开。保护母亲。
I will lure it away.
Protect mother.
来！
Come!
我们是一体的，
We are one,
你和我...
you and I...
来自阿佩德马克的孩子们。
children from Apedemak.
让我们诅咒这些罗马人，
Let us curse these Romans,
让他们受苦！
and make them suffer!
你在科西嘉岛附近停泊了多长时间？
How long did you lay
at anchor off Corsica?
三周。
Three weeks.
听谁的命令？
Upon whose order?
如果你说实话，你的家人将受到保护。
Your family will be
protected if you tell the truth.
图密善·弗拉维安努斯。
Domitian Flavianus.
我看到了他的命令并遵循了他们。
I saw his orders
and followed them.
把他带出去。
Get him out of here.
现在我是傻瓜的两倍。
Now I am twice the fool.
首先，信任你。
Firstly, for trusting you.
其次，在这种信任消失之后，
Secondly, after
that trust had gone,
因为以为我可以控制你。
for thinking I
could control you.
他应。
He should die.
此时此地。
Here and now.
不，不，他会的。
No, no, he will.
但。。。
But...
当众。
in public.
在参议院被定罪后，将他从塔佩岩中扔出去。
Throw him from the Tarpeian
Rock after conviction in the Senate.
皇帝，滚回去，在我身后！
Emperor, get back, behind me!
请原谅我，提图斯勋爵。
Forgive me, Lord Titus.
我辜负了你。
I failed you.
哦，兄弟，命运玩弄着生命的线索。
Oh, brother, the fates
toy with the threads of life.
把他绑起来。
Bind him.
我想，是时候把那根脏线剪短了。
Time to cut that soiled
thread short, I think.
- 你认为暗杀会救你吗？- 嗯，这是一个开始。
- You think assassination will save you?
- Well, it's a start.
你扮演莫塔，你会，亲手杀了我吗？
You play Morta, will
you, and kill me yourself?
我想我可以。
I thought I might.
哥哥。
Brother.
弟弟
Little brother,
隐藏你的恐惧，隐藏你的眼泪。
hide your fears
and hide your tears.
你还记得我跟你说过的话吗？
Do you remember what I told you?
你不是士兵。
You are no soldier.
那一刻你无法杀死任何人。
That in the moment you'd
be unable to kill anybody.
是什么让你认为你现在能做到？
What makes you
think you can do it now?
- 你低估了我。- 我呢？
- You underestimate me.
- Do I?
无论他说什么，他都会付给你，我会付给你十倍的钱。
Whatever he said he'll pay you,
I'll pay you ten times as much.
- 他在撒谎。- 我是吗？
- He's lying.
- Am I?
我向土星发誓，你将拥有你想要的一切。
I swear by Saturn,
you'll have all you desire.
什么。这是你的。
Anything. It's yours.
无论他付给你什么，与此相比都算不了什么。
Whatever he paid you, it will
be nothing compared to this.
不要听他的话。
Do not listen to him.
他不能见证这种邪恶。
He cannot have
witnesses to this evil.
-闭嘴！-哦不。
- Shut up!
- Oh, no.
听我说！
Listen to me!
陛下将军！
Your General!
陛下！
Your Emperor!
你们这些傻瓜，难道不明白吗？
You fools, do you
not understand?
他会杀了你们所有人。
He will kill you all.
跪。
Kneel.
跪！
Kneel!
我哥哥只是个孩子。
My brother is just a child.
他只是一个软弱、任性的小孩。
He's just a weak,
petulant little child.
所以考虑一下。
So consider this.
谁更有可能让你活下去？
Who's more likely
to let you live?
我和你一样是一名士兵。
I'm a soldier just like you.
我是一个坚强的人，但我是一个正义的人。
I'm a hard man,
but I'm a just man.
我是一个光荣的人。看看他。
And I'm an honorable
man. Look at him.
看看他！
Look at him!
是恐惧驱使着他。
It's the fear that drives him.
你更信任谁？这种恐惧就是你的死亡！
Who can you trust more?
That fear will be your death!
闭嘴。不要听他的话。
Shut up. Do not listen to him.
我哥哥说得对，是的，不要听我的。
My brother's right,
yes, do not listen to me.
倾听你的心声。
Listen to your heart.
想想你的家人。
Think of your families.
想想你所爱的人。
Think of those you love.
最重要的是，
And above all else,
想想我们心爱的罗马！
think of our beloved Rome!
谁是这座城市的伟大守护者？
Who is the greater
guardian of this city?
我？
Me?
或者这个卑鄙的，
Or this vile,
绝望，软弱，
desperate, weak,
卑鄙的蠕虫？
despicable worm?
看，兄弟。
Look, brother.
苦涩的眼泪。
Bitter tears.
你能尝尝吗？
Can you taste them?
我从你手中遭受的羞辱和残酷。
From the humiliation and
cruelty I suffered at your hand.
好吧，现在你可以窒息了。
Well, now you can choke on them.
看，兄弟，命运来了。
Look, brother,
here come the fates.
剪 断。
Snip.
干的好。
Well done.
我活着就是为了服侍你。
I live to serve you.
凯撒。
Caesar.
继续好好服侍我，我就让你活下去。
Continue to serve me
well, and I will let you live.
现在离开。
Now leave.
我会在四只眼睛下和 Tenax 说话。
I'll speak to Tenax
under four eyes.
父亲，现在见到我了吗？
See me now, Father?
我是你应该选择的统治者。
I am the ruler you
should've chosen.
你最伟大的表演。他凸出的眼睛。
Your greatest show
yet. His bulging eyes.
几乎和看叛徒被鳄鱼吃掉一样有趣。
Almost as entertaining as watching
traitors be eaten by crocodiles.
您将成为一名出色的 Aedile Ludi。
You will make an
excellent Aedile Ludi.
你尊重我。
You honor me.
现在清理这个烂摊子。
Now clean up this mess.
我哥哥死于自然原因。
My brother died
of natural causes.
被变质的鱼什么的毒死了。
Poisoned by spoiled
fish or something.
勇往直前。让参议院开会。
Ride ahead. Have
the Senate assemble.
我的兄弟
My brother
死了。
is dead.
有人会说他被杀了。
Some will say he was killed.
但那是谎言。
But that is a lie.
我听说我哥哥答应了一部分收入
I have heard my brother has
promised a portion of the income
从我们的弗拉维安圆形剧场到四个...
from our Flavian Amphitheatre
to be given to the four...
不。
No.
五大派系。
The five factions.
这种安排已经不复存在了。
This arrangement is no more.
弗拉维安圆形剧场属于罗马人民。
The Flavian Amphitheatre
belongs to the people of Rome.
为了证实我哥哥死于自然原因，
To confirm my brother
died of natural causes,
他的尸体将被带到参议院，
his body will be brought
here to the Senate,
你们每个人都会看到没有标记的地方
where each of you will
see there is not a mark
在他身上。
on him.
有人告诉我，我哥哥死于糟糕的食物。
I have been told my
brother died from bad food.
一场悲剧。
A tragedy.
有些人认为我不适合当皇帝。
There are some who think
me ill-suited to be Emperor.
事实上
Indeed,
你们中有些人认为自己比我更适合担任铜珠宝座。
there are some of you who think yourselves
better suited for the curule throne than I.
摒弃这种观念。
Disabuse this notion.
现在。
Now.
愿你的领事马苏斯的命运
May the fate of
your Consul Marsus
以及他在我们弗拉维安圆形剧场的同谋
and his co-conspirators
in our Flavian amphitheatre
告诉这样的尝试是多么徒劳。
tell of how futile
such attempts are.
现在，起来
Now, rise
赞美你的新皇帝。
to acclaim your new Emperor.
凯撒万岁。
Hail Caesar.
订单？
Orders?
保护军械库、国库和宫殿。
Secure the armory, the
treasury, and the palace.
通知军团。
Inform the legions.
给你的警卫细节？
A detail of guards for you?
在远处。我希望一个人呆着。
At a distance. I
wish to be alone.
是的，我的主人。
Yes, my lord.
你将如何供养她？
How will you provide for her?
我正在为蓝调而骑。
I am riding for the blues.
我现在是他们的领头车夫。
I am their lead charioteer now.
嗯。当你被杀时？
Hmm. And when you are killed?
我们车手为此有一个俱乐部。
We drivers have a club for that.
我们节省...
We save for...
好吧，以防万一。
Well, just in case.
你爱他吗？
Do you love him?
是的。
Yes.
我愿意，母亲。
I do, Mother.
爱。
Love.
婚姻基础薄弱。
A weak basis for marriage.
但现在可以了。
But it will do for now.
谢谢。
Thank you.
Tenax希望你来。
Tenax wants you to come.
好好照顾她，否则你会回答我的。
Take good care of her,
or you will answer to me.
还有努米底亚的众神。
And to the Gods of Numidia.
你的新家？
Your new home?
天蝎座没有使用它。
Scorpus isn't using it.
无论如何，他讨厌它。
Anyway, he hated it.
他更喜欢妓院。
He preferred brothels.
图密善，我们的新皇帝，让我成为埃迪尔·卢迪。
Domitian, our new emperor,
has made me Aedile Ludi.
你知道这意味着什么吗？
You know what that means?
尤利乌斯·凯撒本人
Julius Caesar himself
在他崛起期间担任 Aedile。
served as Aedile
during his rise.
当之无愧的奖品。
A deserved prize.
为了让新皇帝登上王位。
For putting a new
emperor on the throne.
现在我们都知道了，
Now we both know that,
但不能大声说出来。
but it's not to
be said out loud.
尤其是对图密善。
Especially to Domitian.
你明白我需要杀了你，不是吗？
You understand that I
need to kill you, don't you?
我知道你相信这一点。
I understand that
you believe that.
那么，这并不奇怪。
No surprise, then.
我希望你能试着讨价还价。
I expected you to try and
bargain your way out of this.
只有靠着愚蠢的运气，我才能活着。
It's only through
dumb luck that I'm alive.
如果那卷轴传到提多那里，
Had that scroll reached Titus,
我会死的，图密善也会死。
I would be dead,
and Domitian as well.
那么你应该感谢你的罗马神，福尔图纳。
Then you should thank
your Roman god, Fortuna.
我愿意。
I do.
我不乐意杀了你。
I take no pleasure
in killing you.
但你让我别无选择。
But you've given me no choice.
我背叛了你。
I betrayed you.
但是我曾经骗过你吗？
But did I ever lie to you?
你来自阴沟，
You are from the gutter,
你的钱，
your money,
你的赌注，你的盟友，
your betting, your allies,
你所有的效忠，你的存在，
all your allegiances,
your very being,
下水道都散发着臭味。
all reek of the sewer.
但你现在住在埃斯奎林山上。
But you live on the
Esquiline Hill now.
你需要一个诚实的人来管理你留下的东西。
You need someone honest to
manage what you leave behind.
没有无穷无尽的资金流，
Without an endless
flow of money,
这一切都会分崩离析，
all this will fall apart,
参议员们会笑着滚动
and the senators
will roll with laughter
当他们把你踢回排水沟时。
as they kick you
back to the gutter.
我为什么要相信你？
Why should I trust you?
还有谁？
Who else?
为了我的孩子，
For my children,
我一会儿就会背叛你。
I will betray you in a second.
但除此之外，我永远不会对你撒谎。
But beyond that, I
will never lie to you.
我从来没有。
I never have.
还有谁能为你提供？
Who else can offer you that?
你吓死我了。
You terrify me.
好。
Good.
你知道在哪里可以找到我。
You know where to find me.
我杀了一个皇帝，
I killed an emperor,
但回报是成为 Aedile Ludi。
but the reward was
to become Aedile Ludi.
这只是我旅程的第一步。
This was only a first
step in my journey.
在某个时候，我将前往锡拉丘兹，
At some point, I will
travel to Syracuse,
看看我是否真的是贵族，
to find out if I'm
truly a patrician,
正如乌尔苏斯告诉我的那样。
as Ursus told me.
也许这将伴随着一些我会继承的土地。
Maybe this will come with
some land I would inherit.
我们拭目以待。
We will see.
我需要提防图密善。
I need to be
watchful of Domitian.
他就像一个任性的孩子。
He's like a petulant child.
残酷
Cruel,
以及一个不可预测的阴谋家和杀手。
and an unpredictable
schemer and killer.
希望
Hopefully,
我将能够控制他。
I will be able to control him.
让游戏开始吧。
Let the games begin.